Wonder by RJ
[Music]
palasio Daisy's toys JUSTIN CAME OVER about half an hour
later. He gave me a big hug and said: “Sorry Augie We all sat down in the
living room, not saying anything. For some reason the and I had taken all of
Daisy’s toys from around the house and had put them in a little pile on the
coffee table. Now we just stared at the pile. “She really is the greatest dog in
the world,” said Via. “I know,” said Justin, rubbing Via’s back. “She just started
whimpering, like all of a sudden?” I said.
Via nodded. “Like 2 seconds after you left the table,” she said. “Mom was going to go
after you, but Daisy just started, like, whimpering.” “Like how?” I said.
“Just whimpering, I don’t know,” said Via.
“Like howling?” I asked auggy like whimpering!” she answered
impatiently. “She just started moaning, like something was really hurting her.
And she was panting like crazy. Then she just kind of flopped down, and Mom went
over and tried to pick her up, and whatever, she was obviously hurting. She
bit Mom.” “What?” I said. “When Mom tried to touch her stomach, Daisy bit her hand,” Via
explained. “Daisy never bites anybody!” I answered. “She wasn’t herself,” said Justin.
“She was obviously in pain.” “Daddy was right,” said Via. “We shouldn’t have let her
get this bad.” “What do you mean?” I said. “He knew she was sick?”
“Auggie, Mom’s taken her to the vet like three times in the last two months. She’s
been throwing up left and right. Haven’t you noticed?” “But I didn’t know she was
sick!” Via didn’t say anything, but she put her arm around my shoulders and pulled
me closer to her. I started to cry again. “I’m sorry, Auggie,” she said softly.
“I’m really sorry about everything, okay?
You forgive me? You know how much I love you, right?” I nodded. Somehow that fight didn’t
matter much now. “Was Mommy bleeding?” I asked. “It was
just a nip,” said Via. “Right there.” She pointed to the bottom of her thumb to
show me exactly where Daisy had bitten Mom. “Did it hurt her?” “Mommy’s okay, Auggie.
She’s fine.” Mom and Dad came home 2 hours later. We knew the second they opened the
door and Daisy wasn’t with them that Daisy was gone. We all sat down in the
living room around the pile of Daisy’s toys. Dad told us what happened at the
animal hospital, how the vet took Daisy for some X-rays and blood tests and came
back and told them she had a huge mass in her stomach. She was having trouble
breathing. Mom and Dad didn’t want her to suffer, so Daddy picked her up in his
arms like he always liked to do, with her legs straight up in the air, and he and
Mom kissed her goodbye over burn over again and whispered to her while the vet
put the needle into her leg. And then after about a minute she died in Daddy’s
arms. It was so peaceful, Daddy said. She wasn’t in any pain at all. Like she was
just going to sleep. A couple of times while he talked,
Dad’s voice got trembly and he cleared his throat. I’ve never seen Dad cry before,
but I saw him cry tonight. I had gone into Mom and Dad’s bedroom looking for
Mom to put me to bed I saw Dad sitting
on the edge of the bed, taking off his socks. His back was to the door, so he
didn’t know I was there. At first I thought he was laughing because his
shoulders were shaking, but then he put his palms on his eyes and I realized he
was crying. It was the quietest crying I’ve ever heard. Like a whisper. I was
going to go over to him, but then I thought thought maybe he was whisper
crying because he didn’t want me or anyone else to hear him. So I walked out
and went to Via’s room, and I saw Mom
lying next to Via on the bed, and Mom was whispering to Via, who was
crying. So I went to my bed and put on my pajamas without anyone telling me to and
put the NightLight on and turned the light off and crawled into the little
mountain of stuffed animals I had left on my bed earlier. It felt like that all had
happened a million years ago. I took my hearing aids off and put them on the
night table and pulled the covers up to my ears and imagine Daisy snuggling with
me, her big wet tongue licking my face all over like it was her favorite face
in the world. And that’s how I fell asleep Heaven I WOKE UP later on and it
was still dark. I got out of bed and walked into Mom and Dad’s bedroom. “Mommy?”
I whispered. It was completely dark, so I couldn’t see her open her eyes. “Mommy?” “You
okay, honey?” she said groggy Can I sleep with you?” Mom scooted
over towards Daddy’s side of the bed, and I snuggled up next to her. She kissed my
hair. “Is your hand okay?” I said. “Via told
me Daisy bit you.” “It was only a nip,” she whispered in my
ear. “Mommy I started Ed crying. “I’m sorry about what I said sh There’s nothing to
be sorry about,” she said, so quietly I could barely hear her. She was rubbing
the sight of her face against my face. “Is Via ashamed of me?” I
said. “No, honey, no. You know she’s not.
She’s just adjusting to a new school.
It’s not easy.” “I know.” “I know you know.” “I’m
sorry I called you a liar.” “Go to sleep,
sweet boy. I love you so much.” “I love you so much, too, Mommy.” “Good night, honey,” she
said very softly. “Mommy, is Daisy with GRS now?” “I think so.” “Are they in heaven?” “Yes.” “Do
people look the same when they get to heaven uh I don’t know. I don’t think
so.” “Then how do people recognize each other?” “I don’t know, sweetie.” She sounded
tired. “They just feel it. You don’t need your eyes to love, right? You just feel it
inside you. That’s how it is in heaven.
It’s just love, and no one forgets who they love.” She kissed me
again. “Now go to sleep, honey.
It’s late. And I’m so tired.” But I couldn’t go to sleep, even
after I knew she had fallen asleep. I could hear Daddy sleeping,
too, and I imagined I could hear Via sleeping down the hallway in her room.
And I wondered if Daisy was sleeping in heaven right then. And if she was
sleeping, was she dreaming about me? And I wondered how it would feel to be in heaven someday
and not have my face matter anymore. Just like it never, ever mattered to Daisy
understudy VIA BROUGHT HOME three tickets to her school play a few days
after Daisy died. We never mentioned the fight we had over dinner again. On the
night of the play, right before she and Justin were leaving to get to their
school early, she gave me a big hug and told me she loved me and she was proud
to be my sister. This was my first time in Via’s new school. It was much bigger
than her old school, and a thousand times bigger than my school. More hallways. More
room for people. The only really bad thing about my bionic Lobot hearing aids
was the fact that I couldn’t wear a baseball cap anymore. In situations like
these, baseball caps came in really handy.
Sometimes I wish I could still get away with wearing that old astronaut helmet I
used to wear when I was little. Believe it or not, people would think seeing a
kid in an astronaut helmet was a lot less weird than seeing my face. Anyway, I
kept my head down as I walked right behind Mom through the long bright hallways. We followed the
crowd to the auditorium, where students handed out programs at the front
entrance. We found seats in the fifth row, close to the middle. As soon as we sat
down, Mom started looking inside pocketbook. “I can’t believe I forgot my
glasses!” she said. Dad shook his head. Mom was always forgetting her glasses, or her
keys, or something or other. She is flaky that way do You want to move closer?” said
Dad. Mom squinted at the stage. “No, I can see okay.” “Speak now we're forever hold
your peace,” said Dad. “I’m fine,” answered Mom. “Look, there’s Justin,” I said to Dad,
pointing out Justin’s picture in the program. “That’s a nice picture of him,” he answered,
nodding. “How come there’s no picture of Via?” I said. “She’s an understudy,” said Mom.
“But, look: here’s her name.” “Why do they call her an understudy?” I
asked. “Wow, look at Miranda’s picture,” said Mom to Dad. “I don’t think I would have
recognized her.” “Why do they call it an understudy?” I repeated. “It’s what they
call someone who replaces an actor if he can’t perform for some reason,” answered
Mom. “Did you hear Martin’s getting remarried?” Dad said to Mom. “Are you
kidding me?!” Mom answered, like she was surprised. “Who’s Martin?” I asked. “Miranda’s
father,” Mom answered, and then to Dad: “Who told you?” “I ran into Miranda’s mother in
the subway.
She’s not happy about it. He has a new baby on the way and
everything.” “Wow,” said Mom, shaking her head.
“What are you guys talking about?” I said.
“Nothing,” answered Dad. “But why do they call it understudy?” I
said. “I don’t know Augie Doggy Dad answered. “Maybe because the actors kind
of study under the main actors or something and I really don’t know.”
I was going to say something else but then the lights went down. The audience
got very quiet very quickly. “Daddy, can you please not call me
Auggie doggy anymore?” I whispered in Dad’s ear. Dad smiled and nodded and gave
me a thumbs up The play started. The curtain opened. The stage was completely
empty except for Justin, who was sitting on an old rickety chair tuning his
fiddle. He was wearing an old-fashioned type of suit and a straw hat. “This play
is called R toown he said to the audience. “It was written by thoron Wilder;
produced and directed by Philip Davenport. The name of the town is
Grover’s Corners, New Hampshire— —just across the Massachusetts line: latitude
42° 40 minutes; longitude 70° 37 minutes minutes. The First Act shows a day in our
town. The day is May 7th 1901. The time is just before
dawn.” I knew right then and there that I was going to like the play. It wasn’t
like other school plays I’ve been to, like The Wizard of Oz or Cloudy with a
Chance of Meatballs No, this was grownup seeming, and I felt smart sitting there
watching it. A little later in the play, a character named Mrs web calls out for
her daughter, Emily. I knew from the program that that was the part Miranda
was playing, so I lean forward to get a better look at her. “That’s Miranda,” Mom
whispered to me, squinting at the stage when Emily walked out. “She looks so
different. “It’s not Miranda,” I whispered.
“It’s Via.” “Oh my God!” said Mom, lurching
forward in her seat sh said Dad. “It’s V yeah Mom whispered to him. “I know,”
whispered Dad, smiling sh the ending THE PLAY WAS so amazing. I
don’t want to give away the ending, but it’s the kind of ending that makes
people in the audience teary. Mom totally lost it when via as Emily said goodbye
goodbye world goodbye Grover’s Corners Mama and Papa goodbye to clock ticking
and Mama’s sunflowers. And food and coffee. And new iron dresses and hot
baths and sleeping and waking up. Oh, earth, you’re too wonderful for anybody to realize
you!” Via was actually crying while she was saying this. Like real tears: I could
see them rolling down her cheeks. It was totally awesome. After the curtain closed,
everyone in the audience started clapping. Then the actors came out one by
one. Via and Justin were the last ones out, and when they appeared, the whole
audience rose to their feet. “Bravo!” I heard Dad yelling through
his hands. “Why is everyone getting up?” I said. “It’s a standing ovation,” said Mom,
getting up. So I got up and clapped and clapped. I clapped until my hands hurt.
For a second, I imagined how cool it would be to be Via and Justin right then,
having having all these people standing up and cheering for them. I think there
should be a rule that everyone in the world should get a standing ovation at
least once in their lives. Finally, after I don’t know how many minutes, the line
of actors on stage stepped back and the curtain closed in front of them. The
clapping stopped and the lights went up and the audience started getting up to
leave. Me and Mom and Dad made our way to the backstage. Crowds of people were
congratulating the performers, surrounding them, patting them on the
back. We saw Via and Justin at the center of the crowd, smiling at everyone,
laughing and talking. “Via!” shouted Dad, waving as he made his way through the
crowd. When he got close enough, he hugged her and lifted her off the floor for a
little. “You were amazing, sweetheart!” “Oh my God, Via!” Mom was
screaming with excitement. “Oh my God, oh my God!” She was hugging Via so hard I
thought Via would suffocate, but Via was laughing. “You were brilliant!” said Dad.
“Brilliant!” Mom said, kind of nodding and shaking her head at the same time. “And
you, Justin,” said Dad, shaking Justin’s hand and giving him a hug at the same
time. “You were fantastic!” “Fantastic!” Mom repeated. She was, honestly,
so emotional she could barely talk. “What a shock to see you up there, Via!” said Dad.
“Mom didn’t even recognize you at first!” I said. “I didn’t recognize you!” said Mom, her
hand over her mouth. “Miranda got sick right before the show started,” said Via,
all out of breath. “There wasn’t even time to make an
announcement.” I have to say she looked kind of strange, because she was wearing
all this makeup and I’d never seen her like this before. “And you just stepped in
there right at the last minute?” said Dad.
“Wow.” “She was amazing, wasn’t she?” said Justin, his arm around Via. “There wasn’t a
dry eye in the house,” said Dad. “Is Miranda
okay?” I said, but no one heard me. At that moment, a man who I think was their
teacher came over to Justin and Via, clapping his hands. “Bravo, bravo! Olivia
and Justin!” He kissed Via on both cheeks.
“I flopped a couple of lines,” said Via, shaking her head. “But you got through it,”
said the man, smiling ear to ear. “Mr.
Davenport, these are my parents,” said Via.
“You must be so proud of your girl!” he said, shaking their hands with both his
hands. “We are!” “And this is my little brother, August,” said Via. He looked like
he was about to say something but suddenly froze when he looked at me this
Mr. D,” said Justin, pulling him by the arm, “come meet my mom.” Via was about to say
something to me, but then someone else came over and started talking to her, and
before I knew it, I was kind of alone in
the crowd. I mean, I knew where Mom and Dad were, but there were so many people
all around us, and people kept bumping into me, spinning me around a bit, giving
me that one two look, which made me feel
kind of bad. I don’t know if it was because I was feeling hot or something,
but I kind of started getting dizzy.
People’s faces were blurring in my head.
And their voices were so loud it almost was hurting my ears. I tried to turn the
volume down on my Lobot ears, but I got confused and turned them louder at first,
which kind of shocked me. And then I
looked up and I didn’t see Mom or Dad or
Via anywhere. “Via?” I yelled out. I started pushing through the crowd to find Mom.
“Mommy!” I really couldn’t see anything but people’s stomachs and ties all around me.
“Mommy!” Suddenly someone picked me up from behind. “Look who’s here!” said a familiar
voice, hugging me tight. I thought it was Via at first, but when I turned around, I
was completely surprised. “Hey, Major Tom!” she said.
“Miranda!” I answered, and I gave her the tightest hug I could give thanks for watching
please remember to like And subscribe and become a channel member we'll see
you in the next story
[Music]